<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 on Be ambitious</title>
    <link>/publication_types/2/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2 on Be ambitious</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Chaochen Wang | 王超辰</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/publication_types/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Perceived Stress and Colorectal Cancer Incidence: The Japan Collaborative Cohort Study</title>
      <link>/publication/JACCstress_colorectal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/JACCstress_colorectal/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer is the third most common cancer worldwide, and many risk factors for colorectal cancer have been established. However, it remains uncertain whether psychological stress contributes to the onset of colorectal cancer. Therefore, we conducted a large-scale prospective cohort study to confirm the association between perceived stress and colorectal cancer incidence. We identified 680 cases of colon cancer and 330 cases of rectal cancer during a maximum of 21-year follow-up of 61,563 Japanese men and women. Cox regression analysis adjusted for potential confounders revealed a significant association of perceived stress with rectal cancer incidence but not with colon cancer incidence. This finding is partly consistent with that from only one previous study that addressed an association between perceived stress and the risk of colorectal cancer. However, studies on this topic are sparse and warrant further exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prevalence and predictors of prediabetes and diabetes among adults in Palau: population-based national STEPS survey</title>
      <link>/publication/STEPpalau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/STEPpalau/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We aimed to investigate the prevalence and predictors of diabetes and prediabetes among adults in Palau. We used data of 1915 adults, aged 25 to 64 years, who participated in the World Health Organization’s (WHO) STEPwise Approach to Risk Factor Surveillance (STEPS) study in Palau. Information on behavioral risk factors of NCDs and physical and biochemical measurements were obtained using standard methods of the WHO. The diagnosis of diabetes and prediabetes was based on the recent American Diabetes Association criteria. Predictors of the prevalence of diabetes and prediabetes were identified using multinomial logistic regression analysis. The overall age-standardized prevalence of prediabetes and diabetes were 40.4% (43.6% for men, 37.4% for women) and 17.7% (18.6% for men, 17% for women), respectively. Old age, overall obesity (high BMI), central obesity (large waist circumference or waist-hip ratio), hypertension and hypertriglyceridemia were significant predictors of prediabetes and/or diabetes. Diabetes occurred at a younger age in “obese” individuals than that of their “non-obese” counterparts. We confirmed that prediabetes and diabetes are highly prevalent in Palau affecting 40% and 18% adults, respectively. Introducing public health interventions to reduce and prevent obesity as early as possible could prove useful to curb the problem.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The influence of personality and perceived stress on the development of breast cancer: 20-year follow-up of 29,098 Japanese women</title>
      <link>/publication/JACCbreast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/JACCbreast/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is the most common cancer in women. However, it remains unproven whether psychological factors have an influence on breast cancer incidence. In our earlier study, subjects possessing two personality traits, decisiveness and “ikigai” (a Japanese word meaning something that makes one’s life worth living), showed a significantly lower risk of developing breast cancer, although no psychological factors have been convincingly demonstrated to have an influence on breast cancer development in other studies. Therefore, we conducted this follow-up analysis to confirm the association between breast cancer incidence and psychological traits, using the final dataset of a large-scale prospective cohort study in Japan. We identified 209 cases of incident breast cancer out of a maximum 21-year follow-up of 29,098 Japanese women. Cox proportional hazard regression analysis, adjusted for the same potential confounders used in our previous study, did not reveal any significant relationships between breast cancer incidence and four psychological traits: having “ikigai”, decisiveness, ease of anger arousal, and perceived stress. Our finding is consistent with previous studies, and suggests that the psychological traits are unlikely to be an important risk factor for breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prospective study of seaweed consumption and thyroid cancer incidence in women: the Japan Collaborative Cohort Study.</title>
      <link>/publication/JACCseaweed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/JACCseaweed/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excess intake of iodine is a suspected risk factor for thyroid cancer. Previous epidemiological research from Japan reported that daily intake of seaweed was associated with a four-fold higher risk in postmenopausal women, whereas others reported a null association. A major source of iodine intake in Japan is from edible seaweeds, and it is reported to be among the highest in the world. We examined the association between seaweed intake frequency and the risk of thyroid cancer in women in the Japan Collaborative Cohort Study followed from 1988 to 2009. Seaweed intake, together with other lifestyle-related information was collected using a self-administered questionnaire at baseline. Seaweed intake frequency was categorized as follows: 1–2 times/week or less, 3–4 times/week, and almost daily. Hazard ratios and the 95% confidence intervals of thyroid cancer incidence according to seaweed intake frequency were estimated using Cox proportional hazards regression. During 447 876 person-years of follow-up (n=35 687), 94 new cases of thyroid cancer were identified. The crude incidence rate was 20.9 per 100 000 person-years. The hazard ratio of thyroid cancer in women who consumed seaweed daily compared with women who ate it 1–2 times/week or less was 1.15 (95% confidence interval: 0.69–1.90, P for trend=0.59). Further analyses did not indicate any association between seaweed intake and the risk of thyroid cancer on statistically adjusting for potential confounding variables as well as on stratification by menopausal status. The present study did not find an association between seaweed intake and thyroid cancer incidence in premenopausal or in postmenopausal women.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association between parental history of diabetes and the incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus differs according to the sex of the parent and offspring’s body weight: A finding from a Japanese worksite-based cohort study</title>
      <link>/publication/FHDM2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/FHDM2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;objective&#34;&gt;Objective:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To investigate differences in the association of parental history of diabetes with the risk of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM) in the offspring according to the sex of the parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prospective cohort study of 4446 middle-aged non-diabetic Japanese men and women were followed in Aichi Prefecture, central Japan, from 2002 to 2011. Subjects were categorized by their self-reported parental history of diabetes (&amp;ldquo;no parental history,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;father only,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;mother only,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;both&amp;rdquo;). The association of parental history of diabetes and incidence in the offspring was examined according to overweight status adjusted for age, sex, birth weight, smoking, alcohol consumption, physical activity, total energy intake, body mass index, and number of metabolic syndrome components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During follow-up (median 8.9 years), 277 subjects developed T2DM. Parental history of diabetes was positively associated with T2DM incidence. However, stratified analysis by overweight status revealed that only maternal history was associated with increased T2DM incidence in non-overweight subjects (hazard ratio=2.35, 95% confidence interval: 1.41-3.91). While in overweight subjects, paternal history was significantly associated with higher T2DM incidence (hazard ratio=1.98, 95% confidence interval: 1.19-3.28).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our results suggest that parental history of diabetes mellitus is associated with the incidence of T2DM in offspring differently according to the sex of the affected parent and the offspring&amp;rsquo;s body weight.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Skipping is Positively Associated With Incidence of Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus: Evidence From the Aichi Workers’ Cohort Study</title>
      <link>/publication/BFskip/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/BFskip/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skipping breakfast has been suspected as a risk factor for type 2 diabetes (T2DM), but the associations are not entirely consistent across ethnicities or sexes, and the issue has not been adequately addressed in the Japanese population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We followed 4631 participants (3600 men and 1031 women) in a work-site cohort of participants aged 35–66 years in 2002 through 2011 for T2DM development. Frequency of eating breakfast was self-reported and was subsequently dichotomized to breakfast skippers, who eat breakfast 3–5 times/week or less, and to eaters. Cox proportional hazards models were used to adjust for potential confounding factors, including dietary factors, smoking and other lifestyles, body mass index (BMI), and fasting blood glucose (FBG) at baseline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During 8.9 years of follow-up, 285 T2DM cases (231 men and 54 women) developed. Compared to participants who reported eating breakfast every day, maximally-adjusted hazard ratios and 95% confidence intervals (CI) of those with the frequency of almost every day and 3–5, 1–2, and 0 days/week were: 1.06 (95% CI, 0.73–1.53), 2.07 (95% CI, 1.20–3.56), 1.37 (95% CI, 0.82–2.29), and 2.12 (95% CI, 1.19–3.76), respectively. In a dichotomized analysis, breakfast skipping was positively associated with T2DM incidence (maximally-adjusted hazard ratio 1.73; 95% CI, 1.24–2.42). The positive associations were found in both men and women, current and non-current smokers, normal weight and overweight (BMI ≥25 kg/m&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;), and normal glycemic status and impaired fasting glycemic status (FBG 110 to &lt;126 mg/dL) individuals at baseline (Ps for interaction all &gt;0.05).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusions&#34;&gt;Conclusions:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The present study in middle-aged Japanese men and women suggests that skipping breakfast may increase the risk of T2DM independent of lifestyles and baseline levels of BMI and FBG.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positive association between high‐sensitivity C‐reactive protein and incidence of type 2 diabetes mellitus in Japanese workers: 6‐year follow‐up</title>
      <link>/publication/CRPDM2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/CRPDM2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elevated high-sensitivity C-reactive protein (hs-CRP), a marker of low-grade systemic inflammation, may be involved in the etiology of type 2 diabetes mellitus (T2DM). However, whether inflammation precedes development of T2DM independent of cigarette smoking and obesity remains to be confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We studied 4213 civil servants in a local government in Japan aged 35-66 years at baseline in 2002, who donated blood samples and were followed 6 years. Hazard ratios (HR) of T2DM according to the hs-CRP quartiles [range Q1: 0.02-0.18 (reference), Q2: 0.18-0.33, Q3: 0.33-0.67 and Q4: 0.67-9.62 mg/L) were estimated by Cox proportional hazards model adjusted for gender, age, body mass index, alcohol intake, smoking status (current, past and never), number of cigarettes per day, physical activity, family history of diabetes (Model 1) and variables in Model 1 + glucose (Model 2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The geometric mean [95% confidence interval (CI)] of hs-CRP was 0.36 mg/L (0.34-0.37). During the follow-up, 156 new T2DM cases were confirmed. In total sample, Model 2 HRs (95% CIs) for hs-CRP quartiles Q2-Q4 compared with Q1 were 0.69 (0.36-1.26), 1.47 (0.91-2.39) and 1.78 (1.10-2.88), respectively (p for linear trend = 0.014). Stratified analysis revealed that a statistically significant association was observed only in normal weight non-current smokers with Model 2 HRs (CIs) being 0.79 (0.29-2.17), 2.63 (1.25-5.56) and 3.19 (1.49-6.86) for Q2-Q4 compared with Q1, respectively (p for linear trend = 0.0006). The relationship did not change materially after further adjusting for log-homeostasis model assessment or exclusion of past smokers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These findings imply that higher hs-CRP itself or existence of chronic systemic inflammation precedes onset of T2DM independent of obesity and smoking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
